===幻翔字幕组 译制出品===
===飞翔网◎科幻论坛 http://bbs.flyine.net===
快点 别挡路 请让一让
Come on, out of the way. Move yourself, please
来了来了
Coming through
就是这样 劳驾 先生
That's it. Excuse me, sir
Vastra夫人 谢天谢地
Madame Vastra, thank God
我打赌你肯定没见过这个
I'll wager you've not seen anything like this before
的确 自我小时候就没再见过了
Well...Not since I was a little girl
他体格真大 不是吗
Big fella, isn't he?
恐龙都是这个体型 我坚信应该是"她"才对
Dinosaurs were mostly this size. I do believe it's a "She"
才不是 我看过恐龙化石
No, they weren't, I've seen fossils
我看的可是活着的
I was there
那有什么要紧的
Well, that's all well and good
但这家伙为什么会出现在泰晤士河里
But what's this dinosaur fellow doing in the Thames?
一定是穿越时间过来的 Jenny?
It must have time travelled. Jenny?
穿越时间?
Time travelled?
它噎着了吗
Is it choking?
好像嗓子里卡住了什么东西
There seems to be something lodged in its throat
-恐龙怎么穿越时间  -我怎么知道
- How could it time travel?  - I don't know
可能吃了不该吃的东西吧
Perhaps it was something it ate
退后 让一下 让一下
Stand back. Stand back, stand back
它竟然下了个蛋
Well, it's just laid an egg
那是个标着"Police"的蓝亭子
It's dropped a blue box marked "Police"
而且是它从嘴里吐出来的
Out of its mouth
你的生物学真是让我堪忧
Your grasp of biology troubles me
那个是TARDIS
It's the TARDIS
看起来是这样
It would seem so
巡官 我们来处理
We'll take care of this, Inspector
但如果这东西发起飙来怎么办
But what if that thing goes on the rampage?
把这些灯插在河边 还有桥上
Place these lanterns on the shoreline and bridges
每隔20英尺的地方放置一个 围住那只恐龙
Encircling the creature at 20-foot intervals
这些东西做什么用的
What will they do?
它们会发出信号
They will emit a signal that
把那只恐龙困在围出来的范围内
Will incline it to remain within their circumference
Jenny Strax
Jenny, Strax
跟我来
With me
是他吧 是博士吧?
So it's him, then, the Doctor?
一只远古的巨型恐龙
A giant dinosaur from the
吐出个来自外太空的蓝盒子
Distant past has just vomited a blue box
现在下结论还为时过早
From outer space - this is not a day for jumping to conclusions
Strax 不介意的话 麻烦你了
Strax, if you wouldn't mind?
你好 请走出盒子
Hello? Exit the box
臣服于桑塔帝国的荣光
And Surrender to the glory of the Sontaran Empire
嘘嘘
Shush!
博士?
Doctor?
有只巨型恐龙在追赶我
I was being chased by a giant dinosaur
不过我觉得我已经躲掉它了
But I think I managed to give it the slip
你是瞌睡虫?
Sleepy?
（注:童话《白雪公主》中小矮人的名字）
长官?
Sir?
还是害羞鬼? 喷嚏精? 糊涂蛋?
Bashful? Sneezy? Dopey?
（注:童话《白雪公主》中小矮人的名字）
你是坏脾气!
Grumpy!
啊 你们两个
Oh, you two!
绿色的那只 还有非绿色的那只
The green one... and the not-green one
我可能说反了 千万不能提前做出判断!
Or it could be the other way round, I mustn't prejudge!
你们记不记得 额
Oh, you remember, er
这个物体 这个 额 不是我的物体
Thingy, the, er, the not-me one
总提问题的那个?
The asking-questions one?
什么名字来着 记不住名字啊
Names - not my area
Clara!
可能是Clara 也可能不是
Well, it might be Clara, might not be
这就是在撞大运
It's a lottery
-我的确是Clara  -我没说你不可能是!
- It is Clara  - Well, I'm not ruling it out!
喂 闭嘴 大块头
Oi, big man, shut it!
你们也在被恐龙追!
Oh, you've got a dinosaur too!
大块头女士 抱歉
Big woman, sorry
博士 听我说 你需要冷静一下
Doctor, listen to me. You... you need to calm down
还有 我不是在跟你打情骂俏
I'm not flirting, by the way
我觉得有哪里出问题了
I think something's gone wrong
问题?
Wrong?
什么问题? 你重生了?
What's gone wrong? Have you regenerated?
我想起来了
I remember you
（注:《博士之日》中那个机器人头的名字）
你是小手柄!
You're Handles!
你不是个小...小机器人脑袋吗 怎么现在
You used to be a little... a little robot head, and now you...
你已经坏掉了
You've really let yourself go
频率调低
Reduce the frequency
-抱歉 什么  -你那些音速灯 把它们频率调低
- I'm sorry?  -Your sonic lanterns, turn them down
你弄得她头疼
You're giving her a headache
我的女朋友!
My lady friend!
-我就是说说 别当真  -你怎么知道?
- Just an expression, don't get any ideas  - How do you know?
拜托 Clara 你知道我会说恐龙语
Come on, Clara! You know that I speak Dinosaur
他不是Clara 我才是
He's not Clara. I'm Clara
身高都差不多 或许你们应该贴个标签分清楚
Well, you're very similar heights. Maybe you should wear labels
为什么 为什么你们要靠过来
Why... why are you all doing that? Why are you...
为什么联系不上你们
You're all going dark
别晃了
And wobbly - stop that
我们没有啊
I don't think we are
算了 所有人 休息五分钟
Never mind! Everyone... take five
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
这是什么情况 我糊涂了 他是谁
I don't understand, who is he?
博士呢 他去哪了
Where's the Doctor?
就在这
Right here
这个就是
That's him
他就是博士
That's the Doctor
（注: 这里Vastra夫人指的是博士又一次重生了）
好吧 又来了
Well then, here we go again
翻译：祈晴娃娃 逆风的猫 淋雨宝宝 树荫般蓝 夏午维C Jazmyn Freddie
时间轴：翔子 猴子酱 虫虫
总监：Iam_The-Doctor
神秘博士 第八季第一集  深呼气
我只是不理解 我不明白这到底是什么东西
It's simply misunderstandable to me. I don't know what it is
谁发明的这个房间
Who invented this room?
博士 求你了 你需要躺下来
Doctor, please, you have to lie down
这不合理 你看 这里只有一张床
It doesn't make sense. Look, it's only got a bed in it
为什么房间里只有一张床
Why is there only a bed in it?
因为这里是卧室 睡觉用的
Because it's a bed-ROOM, it's for sleeping in
好吧 可如果你醒了怎么办
OK, what do you do when you're awake?
那你就离开房间呀
You leave the room
所以 这个房间是不清醒时用的?
So you've got a whole room for not being awake in?
可为什么要这么做 你们会找不到房间的
But what's the point? You're just missing the room!
别看那面镜子 它正在发脾气
And don't look in that mirror. It's absolutely furious
博士 拜托 你必须躺下 你老是晕过去
Doctor, please, you have to lie down. You keep passing out
这么多的床 我当然会晕倒!
Well, of course I keep passing out, there's all these beds!
为什么你一直这么说话
Why do you keep talking like that?
你的口音怎么回事
What's gone wrong with your accent?
她的口音没问题
Nothing's wrong with her accent
你也这个口音 开始传染了
You sound the same. It's spreading
你们俩都...说英语
You all sound all... English
你们都出故障了
Now you've all developed a fault!
博士 我需要你的帮助
Doctor, I need your help with something
终于有人能正常说话了
Finally, someone who can talk properly
我最近一直难以入眠
I'm having difficulty sleeping. Oh?
我就从没失眠过 失眠从没困扰过我
Oh, well, I wouldn't bother with that, I never bother with sleep
我就是偶尔打个盹
And I just do standy-up-catnaps
噢 是吗 真有趣
Oh, really, how interesting
你都什么时间打盹呢
And when do you do those?
通常别人开始讲话时
Well, generally whenever anyone else starts talking
我就会直接去休息 这样比较节省时间
I like to skip ahead to my bits, it saves time
帮我也节省下时间吧 博士
Save me time, Doctor
在我的精神里投射
Project an image of perfect sleep
一副完美的睡眠画面
Into the centre of my mind
你是想和我精神共享吗
What, do you want a psychic link with me?
可是我的脑容量
The size of my brain
那感觉会像在你头上砸了个钢琴
It would be like dropping a piano on you
那就温柔点
Be gentle, then
我试试 坐稳了
I'll try. Brace yourself!
钢琴来了
Piano
我喜欢猴子 他们可爱极了
I love monkeys, they're so funny
我明白了! 所以人类是猴子 对吗
Oh, I see! So people are monkeys now, are they?
不 宝贝 人类是猿
No, dear People are apes
男人才是猴子
Men are monkeys
现在怎么办 他需要休息
So what now? He needs rest
我们怎么做 怎么治好他
So what do we do? How do we fix him?
-治好?  -怎么把他变回去?
- Fix him?  - How do we change him back?
Jenny 我要回卧室
Jenny, I will be in my chamber
你能帮我取一下面纱吗
Would you be kind enough to fetch my veil?
为什么 有陌生人要来访吗
Why, are we expecting strangers?
不是要来
It would seem...
是已经在这了
There's already one here
我是不是做错什么了
What have I done wrong?
那只恐龙看起来不太开心
The dinosaur doesn't seem very happy
它怎么了
What's wrong with it?
我不知道 只有博士才懂恐龙语
I dunno. The Doctor's the one that speaks Dinosaur
抱歉 夫人 我妻子不喜欢等太久
Excuse me, ma'am, the wife doesn't like to be kept waiting
他从哪弄到这张脸的
Where did he get that face?
这么多的皱纹 全新的容颜
Why's it got lines on it? It's brand-new
他头发都灰了 就那么变灰了
How can his hair be all grey? He only just got it
可他仍然是他 夫人 你亲眼见到他重生
It's still him, ma'am, you saw him change
我知道 我明白
I know. I do, I... I know that
-只是  -怎么了
- It's just...  - What?
没什么
Nothing
如果...如果Vastra换了模样
If... If Vastra changed
如果她变得不同
If she was different
如果她不再是你...喜欢的那个人
If she wasn't the person that you liked
我没有喜欢她 夫人
I don't like her, ma'am
我爱她
I love her
说起不同 她是个蜥蜴人
And as to different, well, she's a lizard
我孤单无依
I am alone
在我足下震颤的那个世界消失了
The world which... shook at my feet
那片丛林消失了
And the trees
那片天空消失了
And the sky, have gone
而现在我形单影只
And I am alone now
无依无靠
Alone
你在翻译恐龙语吗
Are you translating?
风也在欺负我
The wind bites now
世界一片晦暗
And the world is grey
我孤身一人 看不见我
And I am alone, can't see me
没看见我
Doesn't see me
看不 见我
Can't, see me
谁看不见? 我觉得整个伦敦都能看的到
Who can't see it? I think all of London can see it
那个男孩! Vastra夫人正在等候你
Boy? Madame Vastra is waiting
好吧 随便
Okay, whatever
我会送你去她的会客室
I will convey you to her chamber
我可以帮您拿外套吗?
May I take your coat?
我没穿外套啊
Not wearing a coat
-那你穿的这一身是什么?  -衣服啊
- What's all that?  - Clothes
-我可以帮您拿衣服吗?  -最好不要吧
- May I take your clothes?  - Probably not
-你戴了帽子吗?  -是头发!
- Are you wearing a hat?  - It's hair!
不 我认为是帽子 你想让我检查一下吗?
No, I think it's a hat, would you like me to check?
这当然不是真的
It's not real, of course
那这是什么?
What is it then?
政府干的好事
The governments
政府
The governments?
就是他们惯用的伎俩
Yeah, its their usual tricks
Alf 这是只恐龙 是一只真的恐龙
It's a dinosaur, Alf, a real dinosaur
我毫不怀疑
I wouldn't put it past them
Alfie 你不能总是胡说八道
You don't have to talk a lot of rubbish, Alfie
不要在外面待到太晚
See you don't stay out too late now
-你知道我什么样子  -没错我知道
- You know me  - Yes, I do
它的脖子 真的很不对劲
It's the neck, that's what's wrong with it
-它的脖子看起来不真实  -你眼力很好
- It's just not realistic  - You have good eyes
确实 你都看到了 我眼力很好
I do, as it happens, very good eyes
它们是我最好的天赋
They are my greatest gift
-我接受了  -你要干嘛?
- I accept  - What's that for?
你的天赋 我眼力不好
Your gift, I have bad eyes
然后呢?
And then?
-你为什么戴着你的面纱?  -然后呢?
- Why are you wearing your veil?  - And then?
然后我们就被一只大恐龙吞了
And then we got swallowed by a big dinosaur
你大概也注意到了
You probably noticed
它是怎么发生的?
How did it happen?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know. I don't know
我们到处撞
We were crashing about everywhere
博士消失了 TARDIS发了疯
The Doctor was gone, the TARDIS went haywire
他没消失 他就在楼上
He's not gone. He's upstairs
好吧 他变了
Okay, he changed
-他重生了 更新了  -好吧 更新了
- He regenerated, renewed himself  - Renewed, fine
好嘲讽的笑容
Such a cynical smile
-我没在笑  -表面上不是
- I'm not smiling  - Not outwardly
但我习惯于透过面纱看一切
But I am accustomed to seeing through a veil
我那句话哪点逗你了?
How have I amused you?
你说更新 他看起来没有变年轻了
You said renewed. He doesn't look renewed
他看起来更老了
He looks older
你觉得他之前很年轻?
You thought he was young?
他之前看起来很年轻
He looked young
他以前看起来像你时髦的年轻绅士朋友
He looked like your dashing young gentleman friend
甚至像你的情人
Your lover, even
-别闹!  -但是他就是博士
- Shut up!  - But he is the Doctor
他在这个宇宙中旅行了不知道多少个世纪
He has walked this universe for centuries untold
他看过恒星的坠落直至变成尘埃
He has seen stars fall to dust
你大概也和一个年龄相当大的人调情了
You might as well flirt with a mountain range
-我没和他调情  -他和你调情了
- I did not flirt with him  - He flirted with you
此话怎讲?
How?
他以前看上去很年轻 你觉得那是为什么
He looked young. Who do you think that was for?
-为了我?  -为了所有人
- Me?  - Everyone
我戴着的面纱就像他的外貌 都是出于一个原因
I wear a veil as he wore a face, for the same reason
什么原因
What reason?
一个能解释任何事的最古老的原因
The oldest reason there is for anything
为了能被接受
To be accepted
我和Jenny结了婚
Jenny and I are married
但是因为要露面的缘故
Yet for appearance's sake
我们一直在公众场合假装
We maintain a pretence, in public
她是我的女仆
That she is my maid
这完全不能解释为什么我在私下还要倒茶
That doesn't exactly explain why I'm pouring tea in private
-安静点吧  -装到家了 是吧?
- Hush now  - Good pretence, isn't it?
我戴着面纱是为了防止
I wear a veil to keep from view what many are pleased to
很多人说我丑
Call my disfigurement
我不是出于对这种人的礼貌而戴面纱
I do not wear it as a courtesy to such people
我戴面纱作为对他们的心态的审判
I wear it as a judgment on the quality of their hearts
你是在审判我吗?
Are you judging me?
博士是在你面前重生的
The Doctor regenerated in your presence
那个年轻人消失了 面纱掀起来了
The young man disappeared, the veil lifted
他相信你 你是在质疑他吗?
He trusted you, are you judging him?
你竟然敢! 你怎么敢这么说!
How dare you! How dare you!
门! 好无聊! 不是我无聊!
Door! Boring! Not me!
是我无聊!
Me!
（注:马可·奥勒留即"帝王哲学家"）
马可·奥勒留 罗马皇帝
Marcus Aurelius, Roman Emperor
5个古登中的最后一个 斯多葛派哲学家
Last of the five goodens, stoic philosopher
最好的贝斯吉他手
Superlative bass guitarist
博士真的知道怎样组织一个乐队
The Doctor really knows how to put a band together
我墙上的唯一一个大头钉是我15岁的时候
And the only pin up on my wall
钉上去的 唯一一个钉子!
When I was fifteen, only one I ever had!
我不确定你觉得你到底在跟谁说话
I am not sure who you think you're talking to right now
Vastra夫人
Madam Vastra
但是我从来没有对年轻的男人
But I have never had the slightest interest in
产生过一丁点的兴趣
Pretty young men
我明确地告诉你
And for the record
如果有谁能跟一个这么大年纪的人调情的话
If there ever was anybody who could flirt with a mountain range
她大概就站在你面前呢!
She's probably standing in front of you right now!
只是因为我漂亮的脸蛋冲昏了你的头脑
That was just because my pretty face has turned your head
那么不要把我想成那么容易被左右的人
Do not assume that I am so easily distracted!
对不起!
Sorry!
哦 天哪 小猫终于炸毛了
Well, goodness me, the lake is ruffled at last
我以前一直想知道你发火的时候会是什么样子
I have often wondered what you'd be like when you lost your temper
嘿! 你结婚了!
Oi! Married!
博士比任何时候都需要我们 需要你
The Doctor needs us - you more than anyone
他在上一个自己的毁灭中迷失了
He is lost in the ruin of himself and
我们必须要让他找回自己
We must bring him home
你什么时候开始不戴面纱的?
When did you stop wearing your veil?
当你开始不盯着它看的时候
When you stopped seeing it
嘿 嘿 嘿
Oi! Oi! Hey!
巨大的性感女人!
Big sexy woman!
对不起 对不起 都是我的错
Sorry, sorry, it's all my fault
我的时间机器不小心卡在你的喉咙里了
My time machine got stuck in your throat. It happens
我不小心把你带到了这里
I brought you along by accident
我基本都是这样遇到我的女伴们的
That's how I mostly meet girls
但是不要担心 我保证我会带你回家
But don't worry, I promise I will get you home
我发誓 无论多少代价
I swear, whatever it takes
我会保证你的安全
I will keep you safe
你会再次回家的
You will be home again
停下 谁在这么做 不 不要这样做
Stop that, who's doing that, no, don't do that
-这声音来自河那边!  -是那只恐龙
- That came from the river!  - The dinosaur!
Strax! 准备马车 现在就去!
Strax! Bring the carriage, now!
吁!
Halt!!
不好意思我要释放你的宠物!
Sorry, I'm going to have to relieve you of your pet!
你要干嘛?
You're what?
闭嘴 我在跟那匹马说话!
Shut up, I was talking to the horse!
-你在干嘛呢!  -往前跑!
- What are you doing?  - Forwards!
往左! 啊 不 往右 往右 往右 往右!
Left! No, go right, right, right, right!
对不起这是新生的手 我分不清左右
Sorry, it's my new hands. I can't tell them apart
你说刚才发生什么了
What do you think's happened?
我不知道 但我担心是什么坏事!
I don't know, but I fear devilment!
我们不应该告诉博士吗?
Should we not have told the Doctor?
他还没有休息好
He's not ready to leave his bed
注意那边的角落 那儿挺滑的!
Watch it on the corners, it's a bit slippery up here!
Strax 快点啊 现在好多了!
Strax, come on Strax! That`s better!
对不起 对不起 对不起 对不起 对不起
Sorry, sorry, I'm sorry, sorry, sorry
是博士! 他在这做什么?
The Doctor! What's he doing here?
这里有麻烦 他怎么会在别的地方?
There is trouble, where else would he be?
她很害怕 她害怕 而且很孤独
She was scared, she was scared and alone
是我把她带到这里 看看人们对她做了什么
I brought her here and look what they did
谁或者什么能对她做出这样的事来?
Who or what could have done this thing?
-不  -什么?
- No  - I'm sorry?
不 这不是问题所在
No, that is not the question
这不是我们要一开始说的事
That is not where we start
问题是 怎么做到的
The question is, how?
恐龙它自己就燃烧起来了
The flesh itself has been combusted
不不 闭嘴! 你们脑子里是什么? 布丁吗?
No, no, shut up! What do you all have for brains? Pudding?
看看你们 我为什么没有选个像样点的物种?
Look at you, why can't I get a decent species?
全星球的脑子里装的都是布丁!
Planet of the pudding-brains!
博士 我知道你很不爽
Doctor, I know you're upset
但是你需要淡定 跟我们说问题到底出在哪?
But you need to calm down and talk to us, what is the question?
一只恐龙在伦敦的中心燃烧
A dinosaur is burning in the heart of London
除了火焰和烟尘 什么都没有剩下
Nothing left but smoke and flame
问题在于
The question is
最近有没有类似的谋杀案?
Have there been any similar murders?
有 有 感谢女神垂青 真的有!
Yes, yes, by the Goddess, there have!
看看这些人 都傻愣愣的!
Look at them all. Gawking!
第二个问题在于
Question two
如果所有脑子装布丁的人都在傻愣着
If all the pudding-brains are gawking
那他是什么?
Then what is he?
他对他面前这个壮观的场面显然无动于衷
He seems remarkably unmoved by the available spectacle
你觉得他就是那个...
Do you think that's whoever...
他在干什么? 他会淹死的!
What he's doing? He'll drown!
我真心觉得他不会
I very much doubt it
-为什么  -博士已经着手调查
- Why?  - There has been a murder
谋杀恐龙的凶手了
The Doctor has taken up the case
如果我们想再见到他 我们必须也这么做
If we are to see him again, we must do the same
快点 愚蠢的地球人 放在这儿 轻点
Come on, Earthling scum! Position it here Easy now!
对了 小心点
That's it Careful
千万别刮伤它 否则你和你的血系种族
Don't get it scratched or you and all your bloodline
都将在这个时空中消失 非常好 先生
Will be obliterated from time and space Very good, sir.
Strax
Strax!
早安 Clara小姐 你终于醒了
Ah, morning, Miss Clara You're awake at last.
你找到TARDIS了
You got the TARDIS, then?
出于军事策略 博士仍失踪
Military tactics, the Doctor is still missing
但他总会来寻找他的盒子
But he will always come looking for his box
我们只要把盒子带来这 他就会被我们引诱
By bringing it here, he will be lured from the dangers
从伦敦的危险地带回到安全地带
Of London to this place of safety
然后 我们用迷药迷晕他
And we will melt him with acid
好吧 最后那个
OK, that last part?
我们不会迷晕他 这只是老习惯罢了
And we will not melt him with acid Old habits
-泰晤士报 需要我送上来吗  -好呀
- The Times Shall I send it up?  - Yeah, why not?
-Jenny  -早上好 Clara
- Jenny!  - Ah, good morning, Clara
早上好 我们今天做什么 一起寻找博士吗
Morning Erm, so what are we going to do? Are we looking for the Doctor?
街上有志愿军军巡逻呢
We've got the Paternoster Irregulars out in force
如果说有人能找到博士 那么就是他们了
If anyone can find him, they can
同时 Vastra夫人正在为把
Meanwhile, Madam Vastra is slightly occupied
Conk-Singleton伪造案
By the Conk-Singleton forgery case
和坎伯威尔儿童投毒案的凶手变成晚餐而忙活
And is having the Camberwell child-poisoner for dinner
变成晚餐?
For dinner?
等她审问完犯人之后
After she's finished interrogating him
最好离储藏室远点
Probably best to stay out the larder
待会儿会有点吵
It'll get a bit noisy in there later
Clara小姐
Ah, Miss Clara!
你起床后更漂亮了
You look better now you're up
谢谢你 Strax
Thank you, Strax!
不对 抱歉 这是灯光的作用 你现在看上去还是很糟糕
Oh, sorry, trick of the light You still look terrible
我能为你做些什么吗?
Can I get you anything?
不用了 谢谢 我只想喝点水
Er, no, thanks Maybe just some water
没问题
Of course
不用客气 我刚刚喝完
Well, don't hold back, I've nearly finished anyway
放心吧 我刚用这水洗过澡
It's perfectly all right I washed in it myself
我突然没有那么渴了
All of a sudden, I'm not very thirsty
真的吗
Really?
也许是时候
Perhaps it is time then
给你做必要的的医疗检查了
For your mandatory medical examination
说"啊"
Say, "Ah"
啊
Ah
你的嘴唇怎么没动
You didn't move your lips
因为你看的是我的眼睛
You're looking at my eye
没错
Oh, yes, there we are
小失误而已
Easy mistake
这看上去很有趣
Now that's interesting
什么 什么那么有趣
What? What's interesting?
扭曲的自恋情结 消极抵抗的痕迹
Deflected narcissism, traces of passive aggressive
什么 什么那么有趣
What? What's interesting?
扭曲的自恋情结 消极抵抗的痕迹
Deflected narcissism, traces of passive aggressive
还有很多因运动而产生的肌肉
And a lot of muscular young men doing sport
你到底在看什么
What are you looking at?
你的潜意识 是某项运动吗
Your subconscious Is that sport?
很可能是某项运动
It could be sport
好吧 别看了
Well, stop looking
来看看胸腔 就像这样
Moving onto the thorax, such as it is
非常好
Ah, excellent
你有令人羡慕的脾脏
Enviable spleen! Well done
现在27岁 预计寿命会是
27 years old, with a projected lifespan of exactly
别说了
Stop, right there
你的状况非常好
Oh, you're going to do quite well
但要小心水肿
But watch out for fluid retention later
水肿会很严重
it's going to be spectacular
-好了 把衣服穿上吧  -本来就穿着
- Well, put your clothes back on  - They are on!
哦 是的
Oh, yes, so they are
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
如果我们准备共同服侍夫人 我需要你的体魄处于最好的状态
If we are to serve together, I need you in peak physical prowess
为什么我们要一起服侍夫人
Why would we be serving together?
-博士会回来的  -但愿如此
- The Doctor's going to come back, isn't he?  - It is to be hoped
他不会把我扔下不管的
He's not just going to abandon me here
你不要再担心他了
You must stop worrying about him, my boy
现在为止 他很有可能
By now, he's almost certainly
已经死在暴徒手里了
had his throat cut by the violent poor
-咬咬  -咬咬
- Bitey  - Bitey?
这里的空气
The air
在咬我 潮湿又在咬我
It's bitey, it's wet and bitey.
是很冷吧
Oh, it's cold!
没错 是很冷 好冷啊
That's right It's cold! It's cold, I knew it was a thing
我需要
I need, um
衣服
I need clothes
我要衣服 还要一条大大的长围巾
I need clothes, that's what I need And a big, long scarf
不 不 我不要这些 这样会看起来很傻
No, no, move on from that, looked stupid
你以前见过这张脸吗
Have you seen this face before?
没有
No
你肯定
Are you sure?
先生 我从来没有见过这张脸
Sir, I have never seen that face
真有意思 因为 我敢肯定我见过
It's funny, because I'm sure that I have
但我从来不知道这些面孔从哪里来
You know, I never know where the faces come from
它们就这么突然出现了 非常迅速 就像这张脸
They just pop up Zap! Faces like this one
过来看看 来 看看
Come on, look at it, have a look, come on, look, look, look
看啊 满布皱纹 但我并没有皱眉
Look, it's covered in lines, but I didn't do the frowning
谁给了我这张总是皱着眉的脸
Who frowned me this face?
你有没有在照镜子时想过
Do you ever look in the mirror and think
我曾经见过这张面孔
"I've seen that face before"?
有啊
Yes
真的吗 什么时候
Really? When?
当我每次照镜子的时候都会
Well, every time I look in the mirror
说的好
Oh, yes, yes, yes, fair enough
说的好 虽然我拥有这张崭新的面孔
Good point My face is fresh on, though
但为什么偏偏是这张呢
Why this one?
我为什么要选择 这张脸
Why did I choose this face?
就好像我在试图告诉自己一些事情
It's like I'm trying to tell myself something
就好像我想证明些什么 但究竟是何事
like I'm trying to make a point But what is so important
如此重要使我言不由衷
That I can't just tell myself what I'm thinking?
我并非自问自答 你也可以说说你的看法
I'm not just being rhetorical here, you can join in
-我不喜欢  -你不喜欢什么
- don't like it  - What?
-你的脸  -是啊 我也不喜欢
- Your face  - Well, I don't like it either
脸上其他的地方都没问题 除了眉毛
Well, it's all right up until the eyebrows
它们太杂乱了看看这幅眉毛
Then it just goes haywire Look at the eyebrows!
他们充满了攻击力
These are attack eyebrows
你都可以用它们来撬开一只瓶子了
You could take bottle tops off with these!
你的眉毛确实很浓密 先生
They are mighty eyebrows indeed, sir
他们很愤怒 他们比我脸上的任何部位都要更愤怒
They're cross! They're crosser than the rest of my face
他们自我地愤怒着
They're independently cross
他们也许想从我脸上的其他部分中独立出去
They probably want to cede from the rest of my face
建立属于自己的国度
And set up their own independent state of eyebrows
这是苏格兰人的眉毛 我是苏格兰人 我有点像苏格兰人是不是
That's Scot I am Scottish I've gone Scottish?
是的 你绝对是苏格兰人 先生
Oh, yes, you are You are definitely Scots, sir
我从你的声音中就听出来了
I... I 'ear it in your voice
哦 太好了
Oh, no, that's good
太好了 我是苏格兰人
It's good I'm Scottish, I'm Scottish
我是苏格兰人
I am Scottish
我可以抱怨了
I can complain about things
我终于能怨东怨西了
I can really complain about things now
把你的外套给我
Give me your coat
不行 我很冷
No I'm cold
我才冷
I'm cold
好冷啊
于其让我们倆都那么冷 不如把你的外套给我
Well, there's no point in us both being cold, give me your coat
把外套给我
Give me your coat!
不 等一下 闭嘴 别说话
No, wait Shut up, shut up!
闭嘴
Shut up!
我丢了一样东西 它曾在这儿 曾在那儿 那是什么来着
I missed something, It was here, it was here. It was
我看到了什么
What was it I saw, what did I see?
这个就是我看到的！
This is what I saw!
自燃！
Spontaneous combustion!
这是何等的恶行 先生
What devilry is this, sir?
我不知道 但我可能会怪到英格兰人头上
I don't know, but I probably blame the English
自燃
Hmm! Spontaneous combustion!
就像一见钟情?
Is that like love at first sight?
有点像 自燃的原理是人类在毫无诱因的情况下
Huh! A little It is the theory that human beings can
自已爆炸燃烧起来
With little or no inducement, simply explode
你不需要向我调情 我们都已经结婚了
You don't need to flirt with me, we're already married
这当然只是科学界的谬论
It's scientific nonsense, of course
你指结婚
Marriage?
嘘
Hush!
但上个月已经有九篇
There have been nine reported incidents
看似是人类爆炸的事故报道
Of people apparently exploding in the last month
而你认为这些事故并非自发的
And you think they weren't spontaneous
我认为杀死恐龙的人
I think whoever killed the
至少已经犯了九桩罪行
Dinosaur had at least nine previous victims
这些人都以同一种壮观的方式化为灰烬
All of these perished in the same spectacular fashion
我还以为你在画我呢!
I thought you were painting me!
我在工作
I was working
那我为什么要摆姿势
Well, why am I posing then?
你使整个房间金碧生辉啊 来 抬起下巴
Well, you brighten the room tremendously Chin up a little
我不明白为什么我要这样
Oh, I don't understand why I'm doing this!
为了艺术
Art?
为什么要如此彻底地摧毁被害者
Now, why destroy the victims so completely?
很难回答 但又十分引人注目
It's difficult, it draws attention
这样做有什么好处呢
What advantage is to be gained?
你倒说说看
Well, tell us, then
也许是为了掩饰什么
Concealment, perhaps
掩饰
Concealment?
既荒诞又合理
It's a fanciful theory, but it fits the facts
如此完整地摧毁人体
By destroying the body so completely
这么一来 就可以掩饰人体中缺少了的东西
You conceal what is missing from it
人体中缺少的东西
Missing from the body?
Vastra 夫人
Madame Vastra!
Clara 来得正好 脱下你的衣服 放在那儿的椅子上
Clara, excellent Pop your clothes on that chair there
看
Look!
那么多广告 真是叫人悲伤的现代趋势
Advertisements, yes so many, it's a distressing modern trend
不 看这里
No, look!
看
Look
夫人
Ma'am?
好戏登场了 我们得多泡几杯茶
The game is afoot We're going to need a lot of tea
报纸的其他内容
There appears to be nothing of significance
没有任何建树
In the rest of the newspaper
就连答读者问专栏也没有
Not even in the agony column
我们无法知道这是博士发来的内容
We can't know it's from the Doctor
当然是博士发来的
Of course it's from the Doctor
不可思议女孩 他就是这么叫我的
The Impossible Girl, that's what he calls me!
他说了午餐 但却没有给地点和时间
He says lunch, but not when or where?
另一边 是伦敦的另一边吗 有点模糊
"On the other side?" The other side of London? Bit vague
也许是他重生的另一面 曾经是他恢复的地方
The other side of regeneration, perhaps, once he's recovered?
那我应该怎么做 猜猜看我们应该在哪儿见面
So what am I supposed to do Guess where we're meeting?
也许这就是关键
Perhaps that's the point
也许你应该证明你仍然认识这个人
Perhaps you're supposed to prove that you still know him
想想对于一个难以认清自己的男人 这意味着什么
Think what that must mean for a man who barely knows himself
这讲不通啊 博士不会给人出谜题的
It doesn't makes sense He doesn't do puzzles
他并不复杂 他连注意力都无法集中
He isn't complicated, really doesn't have the attention span
所以
So
还是想得简单点
Keeping it dead simple
在另一边
"On the other side"
-怎么了  -不知道 也许是这里的味道
- What's wrong?  - I don't know! Maybe the smell?
啊 明白了 到处都是
I know, it's everywhere
你从哪搞来这件外套的
Where did you get that coat?
呃
Er
我买的
I bought it
哪里买的
From where?
-一个商店  -不可能
- Er, a shop  - No
要不就是 一个流浪汉
Might have been a tramp
你哪来的钱
You don't have any money
呃
Er
我有一块表
I had a watch!
不 那表很漂亮的
No! That watch was beautiful
是我的最爱
It was my favourite
你用最心爱的表换了一件外套
You swapped your favourite watch for that coat
这可一点都不划算
That's maybe not a good deal
-我急着赶路 这里有股可怕的味道  -是的
- Well, I was in a hurry, there was a terrible smell  - OK
不 不 不要
No, no. Don't, don't
不要笑
Don't, don't smile
我还没笑 所以你最好也别笑
I will smile first and then you know it's safe to smile
-你生我的气了  -我没生气
- Are you cross with me?  - I am not cross
就算我生气了 那也应该怪你 好吧 我生气了
But if I was cross it would be your fault and Yes, I am cross
我猜到了
I guessed that
我非常生气
I am extremely cross
要是我没换成这张脸 你还会生气吗
And if I hadn't changed my face, would you be cross?
就算没事也被你气死了
I would be cross if I wasn't cross! Why?
为什么
Why?
换做一个正常人
An ordinary person wants to meet someone
如果想约好朋友吃午餐 他会怎么做
That they know very well for lunch, what do they do?
估计会先联系他 然后问他一起吃午餐的事
Well, they probably get in touch and suggest lunch
恩 那什么样的人会在报纸上登一个晦涩的广告来约午餐呢
OK, so what sort of person would put a cryptic note in in a newspaper advert?
这个 可不好说
Well, I wouldn't like to say
没事 说说看
Oh, go on, do, say
呃 我觉得会是一个
Well, I would say that that person would be
有些自大但又略显自卑 因此爱耍些鬼把戏的人
An egomaniac, needy, game-player sort of person
啊 谢谢
Thank you
至少这点没变
Well, at least that hasn't changed
恩 死也改不掉
And I don't suppose it ever will
我也这么想
No, I don't suppose it will either
不过 Clara 说实话
Clara, honestly
我觉得你现在挺好
I don't want you to change
其实没花多少功夫
It was no bother, really
我看到了广告 猜出了谜底 很高兴参与到游戏之中
I saw your advert, I figured it out Happy to play your game
不
No
不 不 我没登那广告 是你登的
No, no, I didn't place the ad You placed the ad
-不 不是我  -是你 你登了广告 我把它解了出来
- No, I didn't  - Yes, you placed the ad, I figured it out!
看 不可思议的女孩 诚邀共进午餐
Impossible Girl, see, lunch?
不对 看 不可思议的女孩
No, look, the Impossible
来自不可思议女孩的讯息
That is a message FROM the Impossible Girl
给不可思议女孩的讯息
FOR the Impossible Girl
-哦  -哦
- Oh?  - Oh?
恩
Hmm
如果我们俩都没有登广告 那这是谁搞的鬼
Well, if neither of us placed that ad, who placed that ad?
等等 有些自大 略显自卑 爱耍鬼把戏
Hang on "Egomaniac, needy, game-player"?
-这可能是个陷阱  -你在说我吗  -不要在意这些细节
- This could be a trap  - That was me?  - Never mind that
-不 我很在意  -Clara
Yes, I am minding that!  -  Clara
你是在说我吗
You were talking about me?
Clara 对于你我而言
Clara, what is happening right now
此时此刻这个餐馆中发生的事
In this restaurant to you and me
比你的自大更重要
Is more important than your egomania.
没有什么比我的自大更重要
Nothing is more important than my egomania
-好吧 你终于承认了  -不准你再提这事
- Right, you actually said that  - You never mention that again!
这真是个华丽的陷阱
It's, it's a vanity trap
你在沾沾自喜 自以为破解了谜底的时候
You're so busy congratulating yourself on solving the puzzle
却已落入了人家的圈套
You don't notice that you're sticking your head in a noose
你在做什么
What are you doing?
你要是想挑白头发 那可绝不止这一根
And that isn't the only grey one, if you are, erm, having a cull
白头发有什么问题吗
What, do you have a problem with the grey ones?
如果我重生之后长出了一头白发 那肯定是有什么问题
If I got new hair, and it was grey, I would have a problem
-我也这么猜  -怎么了
- Yeah, I bet you would  - Meaning?
太短了
It's too short
-噢  -不好意思 可你就这一根白头发
- Ow!  - Sorry, it was the only one out of place
我猜你也一定想拔掉它
I'm sure that you would want it killed
你这事是打算做什么
Oooh, are you trying to tell me something?
我正试着测量这屋里的空气扰动
I'm trying to measure the air disturbance in the room
好吧 你还真会找乐子
Right, moments when you know you are boring
这屋子里的人都十分不正常
There is something extremely wrong with everybody else in this room
-可是 你不总是这么说吗  -看看他们
- Mmm, basically, don't you always think that?  - Look at them
-不要看  -你刚说要看的
- Don't look!  - You just said to look!
是看 别盯着
Look without looking!
没什么问题啊 他们都在吃东西
They look fine to me They're just eating
是吗
Are they?
好吧 他们没在吃东西
OK, no No, they're not eating.
还有一件事 他们也没在做
Something else they're not doing
他们没在呼吸
Breathing
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
你不想吃点东西吗
What, you don't want to eat, do you?
我已经没胃口了
Hmm! Slightly lost my appetite
-他们还要多久会注意到我们的不同  -没多久了
- How long before they notice that we're different?  - Not long
我们该怎么办
Anything we can do?
你憋气能憋多久
How long can you hold your breath?
也许我们可以圆润的溜出去
We could just casually stroll out of here
就好像我们又不想吃了
Like we've changed our minds
-我们经常这么干  -哈 当然
- Happens all the time  - Ha! Course it does
要不 再看看菜单吧
We could take another look at the menu
他们是什么
What are they?
我不知道 不过别慌 重要的不是他们是什么
I don't know But don't worry, because that's not the question
重要的是 这间餐馆是什么
The question is, what is this restaurant?
好吧 这间餐馆是什么
OK, what is this restaurant?
我也不知道
I don't know
呃 嗯 没有香肠
Er, no sausages?
你这里
Do you
也没有照片 你们这里有儿童餐吗
And there's no pictures either Do you have a children's menu?
特色菜
Any specials?
肝脏
Liver
我不喜欢肝脏
I don't like liver
脾 脑干 眼睛
Spleen Brain stem Eyes
这些东西有那么受欢迎
Mm Is there a lot of demand for those?
我不认为菜单上有这些东西
I don't think that's what's on the menu
我觉得我们才是菜单上的东西
I think we are the menu
肺 皮肤
Lungs Skin
不好意思
Excuse me
好吧 戴着面具的机器人
OK Robot in a mask
那是一张脸
It's a face
恩 做的还真像
Yeah, it's very convincing
不 这真是一张脸
No, it's a face
哦
Oh!
是的
Yes
-是什么  -我们有儿童餐
- Yes, what?  - Yes, we have a children's menu
要说这效率还是挺快的
You've got to admire their efficiency
我这样可以吗
Is it OK if I don't?
有人吗
Hello?
有人吗 经理在吗
Hello, are you the manager?
我要见经理
I demand to speak to the manager
这根本不是餐馆 对吧
This is not a real restaurant, is it?
是啊
Well
这更像是专为黑店提供原料的自动器官收集站
it's more a sort of automated organ collection station for the unwary diner
好比理发师陶德
Sweeney Todd without the pies
（注：理发师陶德，不断杀死前来理发的客人，
并将尸体送给楼下的馅饼店，做成人肉馅饼。）
那 现在我们在那
So, where are we now?
事实上 是在一艘古老的宇宙飞船
Factually, an ancient spaceship
很可能被埋藏了数百年 从功能上讲 一个储藏室
Probably buried for centuries, functionally a larder
怎么还没人过来找我们
So why hasn't somebody come for us?
我们还活着
We're alive
我们被困在储藏室里
We're alive in a larder
是的 冻死我们更为划算
Exactly It's cheaper than freezing us
好吧
Ok
-准备好了吗  -接住它
- Are you ready?  - Go for it
别让它滚远了
Don't let it roll away No
我们就这一次机会
We've got one shot at this
下次变一个滚不起来的
Next time, make one that doesn't roll
走你
Go!
-到了吗  -刚刚能碰到
- Got it?  - I can only just about reach
-每当这时我总会怀念Amy  -谁  -没什么
- Oh, it's at times like this I miss Amy  - Who?  - Nothing
-准备好了  -扔准点
- Ready? - Don't miss!
哦
Oh-h!
Oh
不好意思 我打到哪了吗
Sorry, did I hit something?
你懂得
Oh, the symbolism
你应该弄成声控的
You should make that thing voice-activated
哦 天呐 这是不是
Oh, for God's sake, it is, isn't it?
我不想讨论这个话题
I don't want to talk about it
博士
Doctor?
还在休眠
Dormant
-你怎么知道  -我不知道 只是希望
- How do you know?  - I don't I'm just hoping
会不会是这些家伙杀掉了恐龙
So is it these guys that killed the dinosaur?
如果他们是为了获取器官
Well, if they're harvesting organs
那么恐龙身上可是很有赚头的
A dinosaur would have some great stuff
为什么机器人要偷器官呢 宇宙版的Burke与Hare吗
Why would robots need organs? Burke and Hare from space?
（注: Burke与Hare 真实人物,19世纪时期从墓地盗走17具尸体
卖给医学院以供研究,从中赚取巨额利润）
也许吧 不错的想法
No, but that's a good theory
机器人在寻找零部件  听起来很耳熟
Droids harvesting spare parts. That rings a bell
船长! 我的船长!
Captain, my Captain
（注:选自《啊！船长！我的船长！》沃尔特·惠特曼于林肯总统遇刺之后写下
船长即象征林肯，船象征着美国。电影《死亡诗社》中曾引用该诗。）
他能看见我们吗
Can he see us?
-他也在休眠  -你猜的
- Dormant  - Hoping?
啊 看
Yep Oh, look!
还在充电 他正在睡着
He's recharging He's asleep
-根本不知道我们在这  -你确定吗
- Doesn't even know we're here  - Are you sure?
确定 不确定 反正就这两种可能
Sure, not sure one or the other
一半人 一半机器 一个生化人 是吧
OK, so half-man, half-robot A cyborg, yeah?
-哦  -哦
- Oh  - Oh?
哦~ 哦?
Oh-h Oh?
看看他的手
Look at the hands
他的手怎么了
What about them?
-仔细看  -我在看着呢
- Look at them  - I'm looking
这两只手不一样大 分别来自不同的身体
They don't match These hands don't belong to the same body
我不明白你的意思
I don't understand
没关系
I don't blame you
看这里 这不是传统意义上的生化人
See, this, this is not your normal cyborg
并不是一个人 试图将自己变成机器人
This isn't a man turning himself into a robot
而是一个机器人想把自己 一点 一点的 变成人
This is a robot turning himself into a man, piece by piece
可那间餐馆是用来做什么的
That's what the restaurant's for
总是需要有持续新鲜的器官供应
Well, it would need a constant supply of spare parts
皮肤只会干枯 但器官却会腐烂
You can tan skin, but organs rot
这里的金属看上去来自罗马时期
Some of that metalwork looks Roman
我想知道他造出来多久了
Wonder how long it's been around
有多少部件没有换过
How much of the original is even left
眼球看上去却是很新鲜
The eyeballs look very fresh, though Eugh!
啊啊
Aggh!
它是不是醒了?
Is it awake?
正在苏醒 我估计
It's waking up... I think
好了 我们走
OK, let's go
我以前见过这一幕 我一定是遗漏了什么!
I've seen this before. I'm missing something!
-博士!  -这是一个全新的大脑 正在重启!
- Doctor!  - It's the brand-new head, rebooting!
快来吧!
Come on!
我之前看到过!
I've seen this before!
噢 快点 出去
Oh, hurry up, get out
博士!
Doctor!
快!
Quickly!
抱歉 太慢了 没理由让我们俩都被抓住
Sorry, too slow. There's no point in them catching us both
好吧至少把起子给我!
Well, give me the screwdriver!
抱歉 太慢了 没理由让我们俩都被抓住
Sorry, too slow. There's no point in them catching us both
好吧至少把起子给我!
Well, give me the screwdriver!
我可能会用到
I might need it
博士?
Doctor?
他们还有些手段没有用呢
Something else they're not doing
深呼吸
Breathing
你能闭气多久
How long can you hold your breath?
把她带过来
Bring her
够了 住手 全都给我住手
All right, stop. Stop it, all of you, now
啊哈! 她是新来的
Ha-ha! It's her first day
如果再不住手
If you don't stop it
我就把你们一个个的
I'm going to have each and every single one of you
都从学校里踢出去!
kicked out of this school!
那就来啊 动手啊
Go on, then. Do it!
另一个在哪里?
Where is the other one?
还有一个人  他在哪?
There was another. Where is he?
另一个在哪?
Where is the other?
你会告诉我们...
You will tell us...
不然你会被毁灭
..Or you will be destroyed
你说什么?
What did you say?
你会告诉我们
You will tell us
-是 我知道 不然怎样?  -你会死亡
- Yeah, I know, or what?  - You will die
那就来啊
Go on, then
动手吧
Do it
那就来啊
Go on, then
动手吧
Do it
我不会回答你的任何问题的
I'm not going to answer any of your questions
所以你只剩这条路了 杀了我吧
So you have to do it. You have to kill me
你不执行 威胁是毫无用处的
Threats don't work unless you deliver
-你会告诉我们另一个在哪里  -不
- You will tell us where the other one is  - Nope
-你会被抹杀  -那就来抹杀我啊
- You will be destroyed  - Destroy me, then
如果你不动手的话...
And if you don't, then...
我将不会相信你对我做出的任何威胁
I not going to believe a single threat you make from now on
当然 如果我死了 那么
Of course, if I'm dead, then...
我就不能告诉你另一个人去哪了 那么
I can't tell you where the other one went, then...
你就只能把这个地方变成一个死寂的秘密 不是吗?
You need to keep this place down here a secret, don't you?
别一开始就动用终极制裁
Never start with your final sanction
那么你除了退步 无路可走
You've got nowhere to go but backwards
人类会感受到痛楚
Humans feel pain
大的威胁到小的威胁 懂我的意思了吧? 让步
Bigger threat to smaller threat - see what I mean? Backwards
我们可以通过折磨你 来获取信息
The information can be extracted by means of your suffering
你是在吓我吗?
Are you trying to scare me?
因为我已经被死吓的够呛了
Well, cos I'm already bloody terrified of dying...
在我交出保命的信息前
And I'll endure a lot of pain
我能忍受很长一段时间的痛苦
For a very long time before I give up the information
但你又有多少时间呢?
that's keeping me alive. How long have you got?
你能给我的只有我的生命
All you can offer me is my life
而你不能做的就是威胁
what you can't do is threaten it
我们来谈谈条件吧
You can negotiate
好 好 好了! 好 对
OK, OK, OK! OK, yes
是 是 被你吓哭了
yes, yes, I'm crying
只是因为我被你吓到
And it's just because I am very frightened of you
如果你对人类的事情有一点了解
If you know anything about human beings
你就会知道 你摊上事儿了
that means you... you're in a lot trouble
我们不会谈判
We will not negotiate
你没得选择
You don't have a choice
告诉你吧 如果你回答我的问题 那我也回答你的
I tell you what, I'll answer your questions if you answer mine
我们不会回答问题
We will not answer questions
我们轮着来 我先来 你们为什么要杀死恐龙?
We'll take turns, I'll go first. Why did you kill the dinosaur?
-我们不会回答问题  -你们为什么要杀死恐龙?
-We will not answer questions  - Why did you kill the dinosaur?
-我们不会回答问题!  -那你最好还是杀了我吧
- We will not answer questions!  - Then you might as well kill me
除非你们回答我 否则我不会再说话了
Because I'm not talking again till you do
恐龙的视神经里有一种材料
Within the optic nerve of the dinosaur is material of use
和我们的计算机系统吻合
To our computer systems
你们把整头恐龙烧死就为了一个零件?
You burned a whole dinosaur for a spare part?
不 不对 等一下
No, no, hang on
你知道恐龙的视神经里面有什么
You know what's in a dinosaur's optic nerve
意味着你们之前见过他们
which means you've seen them before
另一个人在哪?
Where is the other one?
你们重建自身多久了?
How long have you been rebuilding yourselves?
看看你们自己的样子!
Look at the state of you!
可还剩下一点自己原来的部分吗? 有什么意义吗?
Is there any real you left? What's the point?
（注:The promised land:圣经中 上帝耶和华向犹太人的祖先 亚伯拉罕的后裔应许赐给的丰沃土地）
我们会到达应许之地
We will reach the promised land
哪里 应许之地? 那是什么?
The what, the promised land? What's that?
另一个人在哪里?
Where is the other one?
我不知道
I don't know
但是我知道他会在哪里 他一直都在的地方
But I know where he will be... where he will always be
如果博士还是那个博士...
If the Doctor is still the Doctor...
他会回来救我
He will have my back
我是对的 是吧? 求你了 求你了上帝 说我是对的
I'm right, aren't I? Go on. Please, please, God, say I'm right
嗨 嗨 来自远古时代的垃圾机器人
Hello, hello, rubbish robots from the dawn of time
感谢你们无偿提供的信息
Thank you for all the gratuitous information
哭鼻子去吧小个子 你们从来没有过希望
Five foot one and crying - you never stood a chance
停下吧
Stop it!
这是你们的能量源 虽然很微弱
This is your power source, and feeble though it is
我还是可以用它炸掉整个房间
I can use it to blow this whole room
如果我看到一点点我不喜欢的东西
If I see one thing that I don't like
包括卡拉OK和哑剧 所以别轻举妄动
And that includes karaoke and mime, so take no chances
看到了吗 Clara
See, Clara?
（注:Droid 曾出现在电影星球大战中的人形机器人 从词语Android中创造而来）
怎样把自己伪装成一个机器人
That's how you disguise yourself as a Droid
没错 但我根本没多少时间
Yeah, well, I didn't have a lot of time
我突然被抛弃了
I'd been suddenly abandoned
对不起 好不 不 事实上我不会的
Sorry. Well, no, actually I'm not
你充满激情的样子棒极了
You're brilliant on adrenaline
这远超出你的能力范围了 先生
And you were out of your depth, sir
不要试图去控制一个控制狂
Never try and control a control freak
我才不是控制狂呢!
I am not a control freak!
遵命 长官  噢!
Yes, ma'am. Oh!
你为什么在这儿?
Why are you here?
你为什么邀请我们过来?
Why did you invite us?
那个信息? 报纸上的
The message, in the paper...
是你发的 不是吗?
That was you, wasn't it?
噢  我讨厌在大庭广众之下出丑 大家假装没看到
Oh. I hate being wrong in public. Everybody forget that happened
Clare 说出那个词
Clara, say the word
-什么词?  -他们送你进来的时候不会没说话的
- What word?  - They never sent you in here without a word
真不想说那个词  我已经猜到了
I don't want to say it. I've guessed already
勇者无敌!
Geronimo!
原地不动 放下你们的武器
Remain still and lay down your weapons
以大英帝国之名!
In the name of the British Empire!
Strax! 对不起
Strax! Sorry
告诉过你的 走楼梯
I've told you before - take the stairs
噢 看呐 骑兵部队
Oh, look. The cavalry
我毁灭了一种古老的 美丽的生物
I burned an ancient, beautiful creature
就是为了一寸的视觉神经
For one inch of optic nerve.
你凭什么觉得你能得逞 小老头?
What do you think you can accomplish, little man?
你是什么? Vastra?
What do you? Vastra?
楼上的装置
The establishment upstairs
已最大限度的破坏
Has been disabled with maximum prejudice
-而且我已通知了警方  - 等等 她报警了
- And the authorities summoned.  - Hang on, she called the police?
我们从没报过警 都是自己搞定
We never do that, we should start
你听到了吗 想杀掉我们就尽管下手吧
You see? Destroy us if you will
你的餐馆还是保不住了
they're still going to close your restaurant
这话本应该更有气势些
That was going to sound better
那就如你所愿吧
Then we will destroy you
不 你不会这么做的
No, you won't
你是个理性的人 你能约束自己
You're logical. You have restraint
你是为了生存才杀人 你不是个冷血杀手
You kill to survive - you're not a murderer
他不是什么 这可是个屠宰场
He's not a what? This is a slaughterhouse
这里跟其他餐馆有什么不同
And how does that make it different from any other restaurant?
你什么时候变成素食主义者了 一切都结束了
You weren't vegetarian the last time I checked. This is over
杀了我们也无法改变事实
Killing us won't change that
-这样做还有什么意义呢  -寻找应许之地
- What would be the point?  - To find the promised land
你活了这么多年
You're millions of years old
也该是时候知道 应许之地是不存在的
it's time you knew - there isn't one
我在寻找天堂
I am in search of paradise
我也想啊 但是不可能找的到啊
Yeah, well, me too. I'm not going to make it either
博士
Doctor!
我会乘逃生舱离开 毁尽阻挡我的一切
I will leave in the escape capsule. Destroy where necessary
哪还有什么逃生舱
Escape capsule?
这艘飞船已经老得不能再老 飞不起来了
This ship is millions of years old, it'll never fly
它已经被修好了
It has been repaired
用什么修
What with?
你们
You
大家组成防御阵型
Defensive positions everyone
博士 他要跑了
Doctor! He's getting away!
你的朋友很聪明 他知道比起跟着我 还有更明智的事要做
Your friend is intelligent. He'll know better than to follow me
好了 到了 就是这里 跟我进来
Right, here we are, this is the place, come with me
我们意在离开
It is our intent to leave
如果你们想阻止我们的话
If it is your intent to stop us
现在就开始办正事吧
Perhaps we should get down to business
我的老天爷 这次她又把我们拖进了什么麻烦里
Dear Lord, what has she landed us with this time?
餐馆歇业
The restaurant is closed
封锁这里 不要让任何人进去
Keep everyone out. No-one goes in there!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我有种不好的直觉 恐怕我不得不杀了你
I've got the horrible feeling I'm going to have to kill you
我想你大概想要先来一杯
I thought you might appreciate a drink first
是我的话就会
I know I would
小心
Watch out!
51世纪 对吗
51st century, right?
时间旅行的飞船 在过去撞毁
Time travelling spaceship, crashed in the past
于是你走上了回家的漫漫长路
You're trying to get home the long way round
我要去应许之地
I go to the promised land
你一直这么说
So you keep saying
好吧 你的餐馆由你的旧飞船改造而成
OK, so your restaurant is made out of your old ship
但你这是在浪费时间 它永远也不可能飞起来
But you're wasting your time. It can't ever fly
逃生装置是独立运行的
The escape pod is viable
如何运行 你不能用尸骸来修补一艘宇宙飞船
How? You can't patch up a spaceship with human remains
不过 这倒点醒了我
You know, this really is ringing a bell
好吧 干得不错 你用什么来驱动它
OK, that's clever. How are you powering it?
皮肤
Skin
到警局去 我们需要更多人手
Get to the station! We need more men!
我该怎么报告这里的情况
What shall I tell them is happening?
快去
Go!
你估计有多少 亲爱的
How many do you estimate, my dear?
比楼上多 大概二三十
More than upstairs, about 20, 30?
楼上那些不过行尸走肉
The ones upstairs were mere decoys
-这些可都是战备状态  -我已经预见到了挑战
- These are battle-ready  - I anticipate a challenge
不用担心 伙计 我们将死于荣耀
Don't worry, my boy, we shall die in glory!
好吧
OK. Good-o!
（注:Marie Antoinette:法国国王路易十六的皇后）
"SS Marie Antoinette "
"SS Marie Antoinette"
失控的维修机器人 拆分人体
Out-of-control Repair Droids, cannibalising human beings
我有一种熟悉的感觉 可是又摸不着头绪
I know that this is familiar, but I just can't seem to place it
你将如何杀死我
How would you kill me?
（注:蓬帕杜夫人号的姊妹舰:见新版《神秘博士》第二季第四集"壁炉女孩" 其中也出现了用人体修复飞船的机器人）
"蓬帕杜夫人号的姊妹舰"
"Sister ship of the Madame De Pompadour"
不 还是不明白
Nope, not getting it
你将如何杀死我
How would you kill me?
先喝杯酒嘛 这才是人之常情
Why don't you have a drink first? It's only human
我不是人类
I am not human
我也不是
Neither am I
为什么你们就不能死得安宁点儿呢 胆小鬼
Why can't you stay dead, coward!
你觉得景色如何
What do you think of the view?
-我没有觉得如何  -应该说我没觉得如何 我没觉得
- I do not think of it  - I don't think of it. I don't
机器人与省略符的问题 我都能写一本书了
Droids and apostrophes, I could write a book
不过 你已经几乎不再是一个机器人了
Except you are... barely a Droid any more
你的身体里 人类的部分已经远远多于机器
There's more human in you than machine
所以告诉我 你觉得景色如何
So tell me... what do you think of the view?
很美
It is beautiful
不 一点也不美 在这里只不过远远一眺 所有的一切都显得太小
No, it isn't. It's just far away. Everything looks too small
我更喜欢在下面看 一切都很大
I prefer it down there. Everything is huge
一切都如此重要
Everything is so important
每个细节 每个片刻 每个依附于此的生命
Every detail, every moment, every life clung to
你怎么能杀死我
How could you kill me?
正如你不停地问那个问题的理由一样 因为你并不想继续下去了
For the same reason that you're asking me that question - because you don't really want to carry on
如果你死了 其他的机器人会怎么样
What'll happen to the other Droids when you die?
你是控制节点 对吧
You're the control node, aren't you?
很有可能它们会终止
Presumably they'll deactivate
我不会死 我将去到应许之地
I will not die. I will reach the promised land
不再有什么应许之地了
There isn't any promised land
那只不过是你从
This is just... It's a superstition that you have picked up
你填入身体的人性中拾来的迷信
From all the humanity you've stuffed inside yourself
我没有死
I am not dead
你不过是把扫帚
You are a broom
提问
Question
如果你拿起一把扫帚 换掉它的把手
You take a broom, you replace the handle
接着换掉它的刷子
And then later you replace the brush
然后反复重复这个过程 它还会是原来的扫帚吗
And you do that over and over again. Is it still the same broom?
答案是 不 当然不是
Answer - no, of course it isn't
但是你仍然还可以扫地
But you can still sweep the floor
这个比喻不太相关 忽略最后一句
Which is not strictly relevant, skip that last part
你已经把自己身上的每个部分都替换掉了
You have replaced every piece of yourself
无论是机械部分还是器官部分 一遍又一遍地替换
Mechanical and organic, time and time again
最初的你已经不复存在了
There's not a trace of the original you left
你可能甚至都忘了你这张脸从何而来
You probably can't even remember where you got that face from
还不能结束
It cannot end
必须结束 你知道这一切必须结束 而且只有一种方式
It has to. You know it does. And there's only one way out
自我毁灭有悖于我的基本程序设定
Self-destruction is against my basic program
谋杀于我也是一样
And murder is against mine!
Jenny!
屏住呼吸 他们很笨的 大家都屏住呼吸
Hold your breath! They're stupid. Everybody hold their breath
"我做不到 我做不到"
"I can't do it. I can't"
"勇敢点 我的爱人 我可以在我的肺里储存氧气"
"Be brave, my love. I can store oxygen in my lungs"
"与我同呼吸吧"
"Share with me!"
-你比你看起来要强大  -我希望你也是
- You are stronger than you look  - And I'm hoping you are too
都结束了
This... is over
你有勇气承认吗
Are you capable of admitting that?
你又是否有勇气杀了我呢
Do you have it in you to murder me?
下面的那些人们 在我看来他们绝不渺小
Those people down there. They're never small to me
不要妄自揣测我为了保护他们可以走到哪一步
Don't make assumptions about how far I will go to protect them
因为我已经走了太远
Because I've already come a very long way
而且不像你 我不期望能抵达应许之地
And unlike you, I don't expect to reach the promised land
你也意识到了
You realise, of course
你我之间有一个人在他的基本程序设定上撒了谎
One of us is lying about our basic programming
我想我们都知道那个人是谁
And I think we both know who that is
停下
Stop!
你确定他会回到这儿吗
You're sure he'd come back here?
餐馆废墟里没有他的踪迹
There was no trace of him in the wreckage
他们搜遍了国会山也找不到他
They searched all Parliament Hill
他还会去哪
Where else would he go?
恐怕我们已经错过了他
I fear we have missed him
请进
Please come in
-没打扰你吧  -你能来我高兴还来不及呢
- I'm not interrupting?  - I should be glad of your company
我能为你做点什么
What can I do for you?
这正是我想问你的
Ah, well, that's exactly what I was going to ask you
看样子我现在只能待在这儿了 还缺人手吗
Seems like I'm stuck here now. Got a vacancy?
我们真心欢迎你加入到我们的小家庭来
You would be very welcome to join our little household
但我从最高权威那里得知
But I have it on the highest authority
博士很快将会为你回到这里
That the Doctor will be returning for you very soon
哪个权威?
Whose authority?
全宇宙中最了解博士的那个人
The person who knows him best in all the universe
到底是谁?
And who's that?
Clara Oswald小姐
Miss Clara Oswald
也许这人下意识已经打扮得妥妥的 就等着离开呢
Who, perhaps has, by instinct already dressed to leave
我不过是想换件衣服
I just wanted a change of clothes
我觉得我一点都不了解博士了
I don't think I know the Doctor at all any more
亲爱的 看起来 这么想也许不对哦
It would seem, my dear, that you are wrong about that
Clara!
给他点颜色看看 他就是欠揍
Give him hell. He will always need it
-你重新装修过了 -是
- You've redecorated  - Yes
我不喜欢这风格
I don't like it
我也没能完全说服自己喜欢上它
Not completely entirely convinced myself
我觉得墙上的圆东西多一些会更好
I think there should be more round things on the walls
我以前有很多圆东西  奇怪不知放哪了
I used to have lots of round things. I wonder where I put them
我是博士
I'm the Doctor
我活了2000多岁  并非一直尽善尽美
I've lived for over 2,000 years and not all of them were good
我犯过很多错
I have made many mistakes
现在是时候 纠正一下了
And it's about time that I did something about that
Clara 我不是你男朋友
Clara, I'm not your boyfriend
我从没觉得你是
I never thought you were
我不是说 那是你的错
I never said it was your mistake
帅吧?
What do you think?
-谁在报纸上刊登了那条广告?  -谁给你我的电话?
- Who put that advert in the paper?  - Who gave you my number?
还记不记得 很久之前
A long time ago, remember?
有人给了你网上求助热线的电话
You were given the number of a computer helpline
你却打进了TARDIS  谁给了你那号码?
But you ended up phoning the TARDIS. Who gave you that number?
一个女人 商店里的女人
The woman. The woman in the shop
而就是这个女人
Then there is a woman out there
为咱俩的旅行牵了线
Who's very keen that we stay together
你怎么看这个问题?
How do you feel on the subject?
我到家了吗?
Am I home?
如果你想回的话
If you want to be
我很抱歉
I'm sorry
真的 很抱歉
I'm... I'm so, so sorry...
但我真的一点都不了解你了
But I don't think I know who you are any more
快接电话吧 说不定是你男朋友
You'd better get that. It might be your boyfriend
闭嘴
Shut up
我才没什么男朋友
I don't have a boyfriend
喂?
Hello!
你好
Hello?
-是我  -当然是你 你是哪位?
- It's me   - Yes, it's you, who's this?
是我 Clara
It's me, Clara
我是博士
The Doctor
博士 怎么回事?
What do you mean, the Doctor?
我正在Trenzalore给你打电话
I'm phoning you from Trenzalore...
-我不明白...  -还没重生
- I don't...   - From before I changed
（注:本场景是博士之时中的）
我是说 这一切还是会发生的 就快了
I mean it's all still to happen for me, it's coming
噢 马上的事了...
Oh, it's a-coming...
我时间不多了
Not long now
我能...感觉得到
I can... feel it
为什么? 为什么要给我打电话
Why? Why would you do this?
因为我觉得你可能会接受不了
Because I think it's going to be a whopper
而且我觉得你会害怕
And I think you might be scared
但无论你多害怕
And however scared you are
Clara 现在和你一起的那个人
Clara, the man you are with right now...
我希望你能陪着他 相信我
The man I hope you are with, believe me
你想不到他现在有多惶恐
He is more scared than anything you can imagine right now
他需要你
And he needs you
谁?
So who is it?
-是博士吗?  -是博士吗?
- Is that the Doctor?   - Is that the Doctor?
是
Yes
听起来好老
He sounds old
天啊别告诉我 我变成老头了 千万别是老头啊
Please tell me I didn't get old? Anything but old!
我还年轻
I was young
噢 他有白头发么?
Oh, is he grey?
有
Yes
Clara 拜托了 就当是为了我 帮帮他
Clara please, ay, for me. Help him
和他一起前进
Go on
不要害怕
And don't be afraid
再见了 Clara
Good-bye Clara
想你
Miss you
怎样?
Well?
什么怎么样?
Well, what?
他刚才的问题
He asked you a question
你会帮我吗?
Will you help me?
你不该偷听
You shouldn't have been listening
我没有偷听 也没必要 那是我自己打的电话
I wasn't. I didn't need to. That was me talking
你就是看不到我 是吗?
You can't see me, can you?
你看着我 眼里却没有我
You look at me, and you can't see me
你知道我有多难过吗?
Do you have any idea what that's like?
我不在电话那头 我现在就在你面前
I'm not on the phone. I'm right here
活生生站在你面前
Standing in front of you
拜托了 看看我!
Please, just...just see me
谢谢
Thank you
谢什么?
For what?
给我打电话
Phoning
我不确定现在能不能抱你
I... I don't think that I'm a hugging person now
你没选择吧
I'm not sure you get a vote
随便你
Whatever you say
顺便告诉你 这里可不是我家
This isn't my home, by the way
不好意思 TARDIS开过头了
Sorry, I'm sorry about that. I missed
我们在哪儿?
Where are we?
格拉斯哥 应该是
Glasgow, I think
啊 你会很快适应这里的
Ah! You'll fit right in
苏格兰人
Scottish
（注:因为因为博士有着苏格兰音 Glasgow格拉斯哥是英国苏格兰地区的第一大城市）
好吧 那么
Right, shall we, er
你想不想喝点咖啡
Do you want to go and get some coffee or
或者吃点薯条什么的
Chips or... something
或者先吃薯条再喝咖啡
Or chips and coffee?
咖啡 这就够了 你请客
Coffee. Coffee would be great. You're buying!
-我一分钱都没有  -那就去找点钱
- I don't have any money  - You're fetching, then
我不知道我能不能找得到
I'm not sure that I'm the fetching sort
你还有其它选择吗
Yeah, still not sure you get a vote
哈喽!
Hello!
我是Missy 你成功了
I'm Missy. You made it
但愿我男朋友没有做得太过分
I hope my boyfriend wasn't too mean to you
男... 朋友?
Boy... friend?
是他把你推出来 还是你自己摔下来的?
Now did he push you out of that thing, or did you fall?
我真不太清楚
Couldn't really tell
有时他的确很坏 但对我不会这样
He can be very mean sometimes, except to me
那是当然的 因为他深爱着我
Of course, because he... loves me so much
我真的好喜欢他现在的口音 这点估计改不掉了
I do like his new accent, though. Think I might keep it
我这是在哪儿?
Where am I?
你以为你在哪儿?
Well, where do you think you are?
看看四周 你做到了
Look around you, you made it
应许之地
The promised land
天堂!
Paradise!
欢迎
Welcome
来到天堂
To heaven
你到底哪儿去了?
Where the hell have you been?
-这不是我的错 我被一些事绊住了  -什么事?
- It's not my fault. I got distracted  - By what?
你总能发现一些事情 来吧
You can always find something. Come on!
我们这是去哪
Where are we going?
去无尽的黑暗
Into darkness
欢迎来到宇宙中最危险之地
Welcome to the most dangerous place in the universe
他们来了 他们来了
They're coming! They're coming!
亚里士多德!
Aristotle!
敌人在我们的正上方
The enemy are right on top of us!
对不起
I'm sorry
消灭...  博士
Exterminate... Doctor!